Iraq, Baghdad

eminem2014ali@yahoo.com eminem2014ali@Gmail.com Cell phone# 07714099113

Summary of Qualifications

Instinctive and decisive problem-solver **IT specialist** with **7+ years professional experience** in information security and maintenance. Highly experienced with network security, installing and maintaining computer networks, troubleshooting, and designing computer software to best fit needs of company. Experienced supervisor who leads by example through effective guidance and motivation. Also, bilingual in Arabic and English and utilizes strong communication skills.

Technical Skills

- PC hardware and software
- Installation and Troubleshooting Networks
- Installation of Security Systems
- Development of Computer Software
- Router and Switch Verification
- Encryption

Professional Experience (Work History)

Floor Sales and Costumer service

Walmart super center CO.

Jun 2016 – May 2017 U.S.A, OK

- Floor Sales in Electronic department.
- Cashier Associate.
- Costumer Service Associate.

Chief of Technical Department

August 2008 – Feb 2014

Iraqi Government

Iraq

- Supervised, led, and motivated a team of six computer engineers and programmers
- Setup, installed, and maintained commercial security system including 22 cameras and 24 motion sensors
- Installed and maintained Windows Server 2003

Instructor

September 2007 – August 2008

Iraq

GLS Co. – DoD Contracted

- Designed classroom presentations by assessing need and developing curriculum to aid in delivering effective information to students
- Interpreted lessons effectively by utilizing Arabic and English

Linguist

Titan - DoD Contracted

March 2005 – September 2007

Iraq

- Translated for English classes efficiently and aided in effective communication
- Designed, prepared, and facilitated presentations for classes

Editor/Graphic Designer

BLANK CREATIVE

Jan 2004 – March 2005

- Designed promotions and advertisements according to assignment goals
- Edited advertisements and acted as effective team member to produce best advertisements

Iraq

Education and Certifications

Cisco Networking Academy Program
Bachelor of Computer Information Systems
Evaluated Bachelor's Degree

CCNA s Al-Rafedain University World Education Services Company September 2015, (California, U.S) August 2003, (Iraq, Baghdad) Jun 2016, (New York, U.S)

Cover Letter

Dear Hiring Manager, I'm applying for a position at your company. I'm confident that I am fully qualified for your position and will be a strong addition to your team, would appreciate a job interview at your earliest convenience. I can be reached at +964-7714099113 or at my E-mail address (eminem2014ali@yahoo.com).

Sincerely, Ali M. AlShimarry